Preface

At the present time, the preface is a placeholder that contains content of three types:

Notes from Dave to Anke about proposed changes to the book that are significant enough that further coordination is required.
Notes from Anke to Dave, with significance as described in the point above.
The preface, a work in progress.

Notes from Dave to Anke:

Did you ever receive information from any of our attorneys about whether a will has be done after the execution of the prenup? I think the answer to this question may be important for readers.

Do we have any thoughts on the title of the book? We now have four attorneys involved (with the addition of Mr. Gatz to help with probate and wills). Should it be Four Attorneys and a Wedding? Or do we want to go in a different direction?

Where will we discuss the prenup experience in detail? That depends on what you have planned for Chapter 9.
I would also like to talk about experiences in selecting and interacting with immigration attorneys and estate/probate/will attorneys. There may be some detailed stories and thoughts. Where is your plan for where this goes?
I had planned to use real attorney names, but not include any direct negative information about them. That begs another question—do we want to invite the attorneys to write sections of the book? I'm sure that the immigration attorney, for example, would have a lot to say about why one wants an attorney.
What is the accepted current etiquette for whether the woman's or the man's name goes first when both are mentioned? I'm used to mentioning the woman first (i.e. "Anke and Dave:"), but most legal things I've seen seem to mention the man's name first. Thoughts?
Did we want an Acknowledgments section to thank those who helped out proofreading or with suggestions and corrections?

Notes from Anke to Dave:

TBD.

The Preface, a Work in Progress:

In 2020, we (Anke and Dave) reconnected after about 20 years, fell in love, and decided to marry.

That story, in and of itself, would not have been especially remarkable or made an interesting book.

But there is more.  There are attorneys.  And more attorneys.  Did we mention the attorneys?  Old movies would have you believe that getting married is as simple as convincing the local preacher to "hitch" you, tying string and cans to your car, and driving off towards happiness and success.  We did find that the process had a few more steps, at least in our case.

At the time we became engaged, Dave resided in the United States (Allen Park, Michigan), but Anke was a German citizen living in Istanbul, Turkey. Since we had decided to live together in the United States, there was the complexity of the U.S. immigration process; involving forms, documents, translators, translator's fees, procedures, interviews, government fees, attorneys, attorney fees, notaries, and lots of delay.

An attorney assisted us with the immigration process. (Attorney count so far:  1.)

Additionally, at the time we became engaged, we had both individually amassed substantial assets and each of us had our own investing style. A prenuptial agreement was prudent to prevent our individual assets from automatically becoming marital property, so we could have a marriage with a great deal of independent financial decision-making. The prenuptial agreement itself was an interesting journey involving attorneys, attorney fees, notaries, and remote notarization procedures.

The process of drafting and executing a prenuptial agreement that will be recognized by a court in Michigan requires two attorneys—one for each partner. (Attorney count so far:  3.)

Finally, we both required an attorney to assist with wills and estate planning.  (Final attorney count:  4.)

The wedding itself was straightforward, but behind the scenes we had an entourage of four very necessary (and moderately expensive) attorneys. The title of the book almost wrote itself.

It would be fair to characterize this book as an unconventional (übernerd) love story, combined with a practical description of the nuts and bolts of immigration, a prenuptial agreement, and estate planning as we experienced them.

This book would likely have two primary audiences:

Couples contemplating marriage and/or immigration who might find our experiences of interest.
Readers seeking an unusual read at a low price.

This book is not intended to provide legal advice, and is not a substitute for legal advice from an attorney.  This book documents our experiences with immigration, prenuptial agreements, and estate planning; as well as our understanding of the law.  Our experiences may not be representative, laws may vary from state to state, and certainly our legal understanding may be flawed.  Please consult an attorney!

Because there are really two separate stories to tell, from two points of view, most sections of the book were written exclusively by either Anke or Dave.  Sections of the book that were written by only one author identify the author by including either "(Anke)" or "(Dave)" in the section title.

We both invite correspondence about this book.  We would be glad to correct any errors in the book, and we would also be glad to include opinions that are different than our own.  Our editing and re-release cycle is annual, so there may be a delay of up to approximately a year until corrections or additions appear in the next edition of the book.

Anke:  Need to resolve licensing issues.  The Kindle Self-Publishing Terms of Service (or similar) seem to prohibit us from selling content that is freely available on the Internet.  That means we would need to move to one of the following options (I think):

A free private repository at GitHub (which has diminished capability—no pull requests and no graphic views of the branch graph, but is otherwise fully functional, I think).

A paid private repository at GitHub (which has the full capability but would cost us either $44 or $88 a year, not sure which).

I would tend to go for the first option, but you'd have to let me know if you can live without pull requests and the graphic view of the network graph.

We also need some sort of a heavy disclaimer and license in the book.  Essentially YMMV, Use at Your Own Peril, and You Can't Sue Us.

Anke Sindermann
Dave Ashley

Chapter 1: Detroit, Many Moons Ago

This is a test entry to index, attorney. And another sentence to see if I can save, unzip and re-zip this.

Random things that need to be in this chapter:

"I won't travel on an Airbus"

it probably happened in someone's kitchen

mid-nineties Detroit
playgrounds: because we can
the book, the note, and what didn't happen

It probably happened in someone's kitchen. The two of us meeting for the first time, that is. We neither of us remember even the year we met, much less the exact circumstances. While possibly disappointing to those in search of Sparks! Fireworks! Love At First Sight!, that is the truth - our only excuse is that it happened more than a quarter century ago, in mid-nineties Detroit.

Even localizing our first encounter in someone's kitchen is only an exercise in probabilities. All parties sooner or later gravitated toward the kitchen. Parties among people like us, that is - grad students mostly, at Wayne State University, in whose immediate vicinity we were both living at the time, with a sprinkling of undergrads and a few young professionals for good measure.

Word would spread along the grapevine: actual word of mouth, land line phones, and maybe, just maybe, the occasional e-mail - that wondrous invention that allowed you to send a message in green letters on a black screen to another lucky soul with a computer address ending in @wayne.edu instantaneously. Those so summoned would show up with a few beers, some chips and dips, or a block of processed cheese to share; nutrition wasn't exactly high on anyone's list of priorities, unlike minimizing cost.

We were a colorful bunch - people from several countries, various university departments and specialties, and "having a party" for us was, more than anything, about hanging out with people, getting very drunk on cheap alcohol, slightly stoned on the "special" brownies that someone invariably brought, and chatting away. We would talk of movies, argue about books, and try to explain each other the intricacies of soccer (mystery to the Americans) or baseball (enigma to everyone else, except maybe the Japanese.)

It must have been on one of those occasions that we first met, Dave and I. He was a few years my senior, in his early thirties then and an engineer at Ford. We were neighbors, it turned out, living in the same quiet street just off campus, and I took an immediate liking to him. He was a low-key handsome, bearded guy, with blue smiling eyes and dark hair, slightly thinning even then. And - he was clearly the nerdiest person even in our crowd.

One of the first things I remember him talking about with his deep, warm voice, was a detailed and well-founded explanation as to why he, Dave, would go to great lengths to avoid flying on an Airbus.

this requires an explanation why exactly. I only remember as the gist of it that there was too much left to software /electronic components, and not enough simple mechanics

Chapter 9: I Should Have Gone to Law School

Introductory Notes (Anke)

This section is a placeholder for the notes that Anke originally put in the chapter.  I wasn't sure where the discussion of the prenup should go, so I'm placing it here for now.  Anke's bullet points are below, so they won't be lost.  I suspect this section will be deleted eventually.

How many lawyers do we need?

How does one go about finding an attorney?

Are they playing games with us?

The Prenuptial Agreement

Rationale for a Prenuptial Agreement (Dave)

At the time we became engaged, Anke and I had both amassed substantial assets (as it ends up, Anke had about 50% more than me).  I was sure that a prenup would be a good idea for us so that there would be clarity in the event of a divorce.

There were other factors I considered:

Anke has an M.A. in economics, and is generally more financially savvy than me.  I wanted to be sure that Anke could continue to manage her own money and investments.
Anke and I maintaining separate money and investments might make us more resistant to financial fraud and theft.
In the event that we both died at about the same time, I didn't want any sort of disagreement between my heirs and Anke's heirs about how property should be divided.  (In this meaning, property also includes money, equities, and financial instruments.)  The prenup makes it clear which property is separate property, which property is marital property, and what authority a will has for each of us.
The prenup may provide some protection against individual debts wiping out marital assets or the assets of the uninvolved party.  (Medical debts are a special cause of concern, and these debts tend to be hard to predict, and large.)

The Search for the Groom's Attorney (Dave)

In August of 2022, I contacted Marc Nakisher (an estate planning attorney in Royal Oak, Michigan) by e-mail to inquire whether his firm would be willing to handle a prenuptial agreement and estate planning for Anke and I.  Marc indicated that he would be willing to handle estate planning for both of us and handle my half of a prenuptial agreement, but that he would want to bring in a second attorney to represent Anke in the prenup.

I was very skeptical of Marc's stated intent to use a second attorney for Anke (as a layman, I couldn't understand why a second attorney would be required, since Anke and I were working cooperatively on the prenuptial agreement).  I decided to contact a different attorney to get another opinion.

In September of 2022, I Googled for family attorneys with good reviews, and found Blake Lipman in Farmington Hills, Michigan.  Mr. Lipman answered all of my questions and quoted a fee on the phone.  The information I received from Mr. Lipman in the initial phone consultation was:

In order for a prenuptial agreement to be recognized by the courts and to be enforceable, it is necessary that the bride and groom be represented by separate attorneys.  (Any other arrangement opens the door to claims that one party or the other didn't receive sound legal advice.)
The prenuptial agreement has to be completed and executed well before the wedding.  (Any other timing can lead to claims of undue influence.)
Mr. Lipman would be willing to assist with a prenuptial agreement for $500.

After an in-person consultation and the payment of $500, Mr. Lipman prompty provided a draft prenup.

Mr. Lipman also recommended an attorney to represent Anke in the prenup (Chanelle Kizy-White of Kizy Law).  Anke ultimately was very comfortable with one of the attorneys from Kizy Law (Ashleigh Wagner), and selected this attorney to represent her (next section in this chapter).

As Anke and I discussed her comfort level with various attorneys, one humorous discussion we had involved the pricing disparity between Mr. Lipman and Ms. Wagner.  Mr. Lipman charged $500 for his services, but Ms. Wagner charged $1,500 for her services.  Anke and I discussed the possibility that the second attorney chosen in a prenup has more pricing power than the first attorney (because at that point the clients are committed to the idea of a prenup).  We also discussed the possibility that there is collusion and cooperation between attorneys where the first attorney contacted charges the lower fee and gets the clients "hooked", and the second attorney charges the higher fee.  We conjectured that in other cases, a female client approaches Kizy Law first and gets the $500 rate; but the female client's partner is referred to Mr. Lipman, who then charges $1,500.  Because Anke is an economist by training, she was well qualified to evaluate theories of collusion and pricing power.

However, neither of us believe that there was collusion between Mr. Lipman and Ms. Wagner.  Mr. Lipman works as a solo practitioner and has a more ad hoc style, whereas Ms. Wagner works for a law firm with more overhead.  It is natural that different typical fee structures would apply.

Still, the pricing power discussion between Anke and I might suggest a shopping strategy for couples seeking to draft a prenuptial agreement with the help of the two required attorneys.  It might be interesting to try to get "package" prices where one asks an individual attorney to provide a price commitment for themselves plus a price commitment from an attorney in another law firm, as a "package".  That approach, if it could be done, might eliminate the higher pricing power of the second attorney.

The Search for the Bride's Attorney (Anke)

TBD.

The Editing of the Prenuptial Agreement (Anke)

TBD.

The Notarization and Execution of the Prenuptial Agreement (Anke)

TBD.

Chapter 10: Vegas ...

The Investigation of the Legalities of Getting Married in Las Vegas, Nevada

TBD.

The Groom's Investigation (Dave)

TBD.

The Bride's Investigation (Anke)

TBD.

The Search for the Wedding Chapel (Dave)

TBD.

The Marriage License (Dave)

TBD.

Travel to Las Vegas

The Groom's Travel to Las Vegas (Dave)

Purchased Southwest tickets in advance.

Winter storm Elliot.

Was notified by Anke that my flight was apparently canceled (Anke, can you dig up the WhatsApp messages where you notified me and send a screenshot?).

I changed my SWA flight to 12/28.

Anke picked up a Frontier Airlines flight, and purchased one checked bag.

Frontier has the most confusing website, ever.  I purchased "The Works", which was advertised at $88 but actually cost $35 because of Anke's earlier purchase of the checked bag.  This seemed to be the easiest way to get a carry-on bag.

The flight was very late.  The stated reason was flight crew work hour restrictions.  It actually departed around 12:30 a.m.

The staff at the gate were somewhat rude, and stated very plainly that carry-ons cost and had to be purchased, and if you boarded the plane with a carry-on you didn't pay for, it was going to cost you even more.  The tone was nothing less than parochial and threatening.

The captain showed up.  Smartly dressed, tall, caucasian, perhaps 55, a lot of gray, a few extra pounds.  Walked in a straight line.  Seemed very happy and energetic.  Was making smalltalk with the gate crew and cabin crew.  Inspired confidence, especially with being apparently sober and very awake.  I did not notice the FO.

Deicing took a while.  The captain was very careful to explain what was happening in a non-alarmist manner ("be sure it is safe to operate the aircraft" rather than "so we don't crash").  A few trucks spraying on liquids.

Completely rude cabin crew.  Parochial and threatening.  "You've been assigned a specific seat, and we expect you to sit in that seat.  You must obtain permission from a crew member to swap or change seats."

Captain even made light of the airline's a la carte policies.  "We realize you had to make a lot of choices to be sitting in the seat, and we thank you for your business."

Seats had the smallest tray ever (get a screenshot from my video), yet they still required it be upright for takeoff and landing.

Seats did not recline.

Closer examination of the seats revealed that they were at the stuctural minimum.  Rectangular aluminum tube around the perimeter, with a shell that consumed the depth of the tube but no more.  Designed to fit the maximum number of people in the minimum space.

Had a guy that I believe was 50-ish and Polish and didn't speak English to my left, dressed in athletic/workout clothes.  Gave him half my orange juice. During the flight, we were both trying to find a comfortable position to sleep, and we could not.  The gal in the window seat had it easy because she had a corner to lean into.  The Polish guy and I were both miserable.  I finally dozed off with my head resting forward against the seat in front of me.

Frontier is the worst airline ever in every category except getting me there.  Confusing website, a la carte policies, hostile gate crew, hostile cabin crew, awful seating.

Received numerous marketing e-mails after the trip advertising things like $19 fares from Detroit.  Presumably checked bags, carry-on bags, and air to breathe purchased separately.

Canceled my outbound SWA flight.  The website allowed me to do that.

Southwest got a lot of bad press, and had a "meltdown".

My credit as a result of canceling the outbound flight never expire, and I got 25,000 points as well, that never expire.  I would say that Southwest compensated me fairly, all things considered.

Was on The Deuce to find the marriage license office when got a WhatsApp message from Anke indicating she was through immigration.  At that point exited the bus and took a cab to the airport.

Was engaged in a fascinating conversation with a guy who was also an inconvenienced Southwest customer, and was born and raised in rural Missouri.  We discussed pilot's licenses, and it ends up that he earned a license perhaps 3 decades before I did and wanted to become an aviator in the Vietnam War, but the war ended and the air force no longer had a need for pilots.  We discussed how expensive it is to become an airline pilot if you do it as a civilian, and also the high number of mass shootings in the U.S., which neither of us had an explanation for.  Fascinating the people you meet on buses.

Anke and I took the shuttle to pick up the rental car.

Then went to Excalibur then took the bus to the marriage license office.

The Bride's Travel to Las Vegas (Anke)

TBD.

The Marriage License

The Marriage License (Dave)

Went down to the office on Clark Street.  Had our number from the web process.  They printed it out, we reviewed it and presented ID, and $102 later we had a marriage license.

The Marriage License (Anke)

TBD.

The Wedding

The Wedding (Anke)

TBD.

The Wedding (Dave)

Called the chapel (Fremont Wedding Chapel), and they indicated they could accommodate us immediately.

They had provided substantial support and answered questions going months back.

Got dressed and took the cab down to Fremont St.

In a shopping area.  Went downstairs to "Neon Chapel".

"Sign and Go".

Photos.

Neither of us can remember our exact wedding vows.

The Honeymoon

The High Roller

The Groom's Thoughts on The High Roller (Dave)

Bought daytime tickets but got the nighttime experience.  #Winning!  Saved $24 ($12 each).

Souvenir photos, reasonably priced.

Michigan tourists in our car, from a small town in Michigan (can't remember which one).

Paid $48 (I think) for parking because I surrendered my room key early.

The Bride's Thoughts and Notes on The High Roller (Anke)

TBD.

The Hoover Dam

The Bride's Thoughts and Notes on The Hoover Dam (Anke)

TBD.

The Groom's Thoughts and Notes on The Hoover Dam (Dave)

I had originally thought of The Hoover Dam as an optional stop, but at Anke's urging, we stopped.

There was a security checkpoint where they asked about drones and firearms, and they looked at the back seat of the car.  This is something I don't remember from years past, perhaps because drones have become more of an issue.

The parking was in a deck surrounded by rock.  My favorite parking deck in the world.

We saw the film.  Impressive.

We went on the power plant tour.  We were fortunate that there were generator rotors out for maintenance.  Very  impressive.

Reusable aluminum water bottles with cold water out of a vending machine for about $5 each.  Best deal ever.  Lost mine, unfortunately.

Flagstaff

Bride's Thoughts (Anke)

Groom's Throughts (Dave)

Stayed in Flagstaff because Dave's assessment was that accommodations in Flagstaff would be more reliably available than nearer to The Grand Canyon.

According to hotels.com, the four hotels we stayed at, in order were:

Excalibur Hotel and Casino, checkin Sunday, 12/25/2022.

Hotel Aspen InnSuites Flagstaff/Grand Canyon, 12/29/2022.

Red Feather Lodge, 12/30/2022.

Howard Johnson by Wyndham Las Vegas near the Strip, 12/31/2022.

So we apparently stayed in Hotel Aspen InnSuites Flagstaff/Grand Canyon.

Did laundry.

Went to El Tapitio

https://tapatiorestaurants.com/Flagstaff.html

Was great.  Families.  Generous portions.  Yummy carryouts.

The Grand Canyon

The Groom's Thoughts and Notes on The Grand Canyon (Dave)

Got fogged out of The Grand Canyon.  Same thing the next day.  Need to include a photo.  Saw the film.

Stayed at Red Feather Lodge, very close.

The Bride's Thoughts and Notes on The Grand Canyon (Anke)

TBD.

Las Vegas Before Departure

Groom's Thoughts (Dave)

Stayed at Howard Johnson by Wyndham Las Vegas near the Strip.

Was one of the few hotels available at the time it was booked, due to it being New Year's Eve.

Lines to check in.

Fairly decrepit room at high prices, thanks to it being New Year's Eve.

Subway.

Cinnabon.

Sleep.

Bride's Thoughts (Anke)

TBD.

Travel to Allen Park

Groom's Thoughts (Dave)

Drive to rental car return.  One extra lap around the airport.

Long lines to get on shuttle bus.  Anxiety about making flight.

Uneventful flights.  We want through Chicago?  I don't even remember now.

Fractured luggage, but didn't make a claim.

Taxi from DTW to home.

Bride's Thoughts (Anke)

TBD.

Stay In Allen Park

Groom's Thoughts (Dave)

Cleaning.

Thai carryout.

Dinner with friends.

Work for both of us.

Cat behavior:

Cats warmed up quicker the second time.
Anke was a regular celebrity.
Hourly (or more often) bed visits by two of the cats.
One cat's apparent desire to hang out between us.

Bride's Thoughts (Anke)

TBD.

Anke's Travel to Turkey (Anke)

TBD.

Dave's Questions about What to Put and Where

Viagra, sexual health (could be entertaining reading)?

Wordle/Nerdle competition and spreadsheets?

Financial tracking spreadsheets (some sort of a chapter on investing and money management might be useful to some, mostly as a pointer to what to read)?